http://www.qrca.org/page/data_privacy_policy

QRCA Data Privacy Policy - Qualitative Research Consultants Association
This website uses cookies to store information on your computer. Some of these cookies are used for visitor analysis, others are essential to making our site function properly and improve the user experience. By using this site, you consent to the placement of these cookies. Click Accept to consent and dismiss this message or Deny to leave this website. Read our Privacy Statement for more.
Accept
Deny
Events
Blog
Login
Become a Member
Toggle navigationMENUAbout Qualitative and QRCA What is QR Why QR WorksWhen to Use QRTypes of QRTypes of QR CareersMaximize Your ExperienceAbout QRCA What is QRCAAwardsAdvance ProgramQualPower BlogChaptersSIGs Young Professionals CentralDiversity, Equity and InclusionVIEWS MagazineIndustry PartnersPress ReleasesAnnual Conference 2021 Conference Central2020 Conference Central2019 Session VideosLeadership Board of DirectorsCommitteesPast PresidentsGet InvolvedStrategic PlanBecome a Member or Sponsor Membership OptionsReasons to JoinConference Opportunities Annual ConferenceWorldwide ConferenceAdvertising OpportunitiesQualitative Support Visit QualBook DirectoryFind a ConsultantFind a Support PartnerResearch Buyer Resources VIEWS MagazineVIEWS PodcastsQcast WebinarsQualBook DirectoryQualPower BlogPost a Career OpeningMember Resources Learning CenterResource LibraryMember ForumNew Member Benefits OverviewHealth Care ProgramFind a MemberNews and Publications VIEWS MagazineVIEWS PodcastsConnections NewsQualPower BlogAnnual ReportsEvents Calendar of EventsAnnual ConferenceQualitative Fundamentals ProgramQcast WebinarsYcast WebinarsWorldwide ConferenceSIG MeetingsChapter MeetingsVolunteer Engagement WeekMy QRCA AdvanceMy Member Pages
Edit This Favorite
Name:
Category:
Share:
Yes
No, Keep Private
QRCA Data Privacy Policy
QRCA Data Privacy Policy
OPT IN
Introduction The Qualitative Research Consultants Association (“QRCA”) is a global association of market research professionals. We understand that you are aware of and care about your own personal privacy interests,
and we take that seriously. This privacy policy describes our policies and practices regarding collection and use of your personal data, and sets forth your privacy rights. We recognize that information privacy is an ongoing responsibility,
and so we will continue to update this privacy policy as we undertake new personal data practices or adopt new privacy policies.
Applicability and Eligibility This privacy policy applies to our collection, use, disclosure, and protection of your data. It does not apply to third party websites, applications, or services. Before accessing,
using, or interacting with our services, carefully review the terms and conditions of this privacy policy. Services are not directed to children under the age of 16. You may not use our services if you are under the age of 16.
Collection and Use of Personal Information  We collect personal information about our members and other customers. This information includes, but is not limited to, first name, last name, job title, employer name,
work address, work email, and work phone number. This information is used to provide members and customers with goods and services, including membership services, event notifications and more. We do not sell personal information
to anyone and only share it with third parties who are facilitating the delivery of our services.
Membership When you become a member, we collect information about you including (but not limited to) your name, your employer’s name, your work address, and your email address. We may also collect your personal
email address, a personal mailing address, and a mobile phone number. Members may voluntarily provide additional information in their membership profile, such as information about their educational background, number of years in
the industry, and the like. Members may edit their profile at any time to change, add, or remove personal information.
We process your personal information for membership administration, to deliver member benefits, and to inform you of our events, content, and other benefits or opportunities associated with your membership. We may also use this information
to help us understand our members’ needs and interests to better tailor our products and services to meet your needs.
Events and Webinars We host events throughout the year, including our annual conference, webinars, and trainings (collectively “events”). If you are a member and register for one of our events, we will access the
information in your member account to provide you with information and services associated with the event. If you are not a member and you register for one of our events, we will collect your name and contact information, which
we will store in our database and use to provide you with information and services associated with the event. If you are a presenter at one of our events, we will collect information about you including your name, employer and
contact information, and photograph, and we may also collect information provided by event attendees who evaluated your performance as a presenter. As an attendee, speaker, or sponsor/exhibitor, we will keep a record of your participation
to provide you with post-event information including details on upcoming events you may be interested in.
We reserve the right to use any photograph/video taken at our events, without the expressed written permission of those included within the photograph/video. We may use the photograph/video in publications or other media material produced,
used or contracted including but not limited to: brochures, invitations, books, newspapers, magazines, television, websites, etc.
Publications In addition to producing original content, we also subscribe to news feeds and blogs produced by others, which we often link to from our website. This means you may find yourself on our website or
reading an email where we will offer you a link to another organization’s website for additional relevant content. At these times, you will be leaving our website. We are not responsible or liable for content provided by these
third party websites or personal information they may happen to gather from you.
You may wish to subscribe to some of our publications without becoming a member. To receive our mailings/newsletters by email, you will need to create a profile with us, which involves providing us with at least your first name and
last name, an email address, and the country in which you live. We do not share this information with any third party other than to store the information in our database.
You may manage your subscriptions by subscribing or unsubscribing at any time. If you have any difficulties managing your email or other communication preferences, please contact us at data@qrca.org.
Correspondence Information If you correspond with us by email, the postal service, or other form of communication, we may retain such correspondence and the information contained in it and use it to respond to
your inquiry; to notify you of our conferences, publications, or other services; or to keep a record of your complaint, accommodation request, etc. Users may opt-out of receiving certain communications by following the unsubscribe
process described in an email communication, or by contacting our office directly.
Access to Your Information Certain tools and settings are provided to help you access, correct, delete, or modify your personal information.  We welcome you to contact us regarding the information we have collected
about you, including the nature and accuracy of the data collected about you, to request an update, modification, or deletion of your information, to opt-out of certain services, or to withdraw any consent you may have granted.
Please note that if you choose to delete your information or opt-out of the collection and use of your information, certain features may no longer be available to you.
Purposes for Processing Your Data As explained above, we process your data to provide you with the goods or services you have requested or purchased from us, including membership services, events, publications
and other content, certification, and training. We use this information to refine our goods and services to better tailor them to your needs and to communicate with you about other services we offer that may assist you in your
career or otherwise help you to advance your career.
Payment Information We may collect and store information related to purchases if you choose to purchase goods and services from us. You may provide certain information to complete payments, including your credit
or debit card number, card expiration date, CVV code, and billing address (collectively, “Payment Information”), along with your name and billing, and shipping address, to complete payment transactions. Per PCI Compliance, we do
not accept credit card information via email. Credit card information received via fax, phone, or mail is entered into a secure system and then deleted and destroyed.
Website Usage As is true of most other websites, our website collects certain information automatically and stores it in log files. The information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, the region or general
location where your computer or device is accessing the internet, browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of our website, including a history of the pages you view. We use this information to help
us design our site to better suit our users’ needs. We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website, analyze trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic
information to assist us in identifying visitor preferences. Our website also uses cookies and web beacons. It does not track users when they cross to third party websites or provide targeted advertising to them, and therefore
does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals.
Sharing Information  Information about your purchases are maintained in association with your membership or profile account. The personal information we collect from you is stored in a database hosted by a third
party, YourMembership (“YM”). YM does not use or have access to your personal information for any purpose other than cloud storage and retrieval.
We do not otherwise reveal your personal data to third-parties for their independent use unless: (1) you request or authorize it; (2) it’s in connection with any of our events as described above; (3) the information is provided to
comply with the law (for example, to comply with a search warrant, subpoena or court order), enforce an agreement we have with you, or to protect our rights, property or safety, or the rights, property or safety of our employees
or others; (4) the information is provided to our agents, vendors or service providers who perform functions on our behalf; (5) to address emergencies or acts of God; and (6) to address disputes, claims, or to persons demonstrating
legal authority to act on your behalf.
Our website uses interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and others. If you choose to "like" or share information from our website through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that
service. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your site visit to your personal data.
Member Directory Members are allowed to share their information through our Member Directory to other members using this site. Members are invited to opt-in to having their information shared in the Member Directory.
Member information will only be shared in the Member Directory if the member has opted-in to sharing such information.
Changes and Updates to the Privacy Policy By using this site, you agree to the terms and conditions contained in this privacy policy. As our organization, membership, and benefits change from time to time, this
privacy policy is expected to change as well. We reserve the right to amend the privacy policy at any time, for any reason, without notice to you, other than the posting of the amended privacy policy on our website. We may e-mail
periodic reminders of our notices and terms and conditions and will e-mail members of material changes.
Questions/Concerns? We are headquartered in St. Paul, Minnesota, in the United States. If  you have any questions or concerns about our data policies or practices, contact information is below:
Barb Mann QRCA
Director of Member Services 1000 Westgate Dr, Ste 252 St. Paul, MN 55114 USA
Phone 651. 290. 7491 Email
data@qrca.org
Calendar
more
10/12/2020Academic SIG: Monthly Zoom Meeting10/12/2020QRCA NY/NYC Metropolitan Chapter: Revisiting Market Research Post COVID-1910/13/2020How Language Means: What Everyone Needs to Know about ‘Languaging’ Connection
>> Member Resources
>> QRCA News & Publications
>> For Research Buyers
>> Find a Researcher
>> Books by QRCA Members
Member Quicklinks
QRCA FORUM
MY QRCA
Privacy Policy | Email Deliverability | Site Map | Sign Out © 2020 QRCA
This website is optimized for Firefox and Chrome. If you have difficulties using this site, see complete browser details.
Association Management Software Powered by YourMembership  ::  Legal
